纽泽西州纽沃市 九月
汤尼 别忘了告诉路易叔叔…我把红酒和巴马干酪留在冰箱里
Don't forget to tell Uncle Louie I left the red wine and Parmesan in the fridge.
拜拜 好
I love you. Bye -bye.
-拜拜 裘蒂 -寄照片来喔
-'Bye, Judy. -Send me a picture.
我很快回来 别担心
I'll be back soon. Don't worry about it.
-小心点 -拜
-Be careful, now. -Bye.
-保重啦 -拜!
-Take it easy, now. -'Bye.
加州 我们来啦
"California, here we come"
来 丹尼尔 怎么啦? 不喜欢我唱歌?
What's wrong? Don't you like my singing?
妈 我不喜欢那首歌
I don't like the song.
你会喜欢加州的 你早上起床
You're going to love California. You get up in the morning...
滚出床外 咚! 就掉进游泳池里了
... roll out of bed, plop, in the pool.
是哦
Yeah, sure.
你看着吧 我们要搬进的可不是破旧小屋喔
You'll see. This isn't exactly a dump we're moving to.
峡谷口汽车旅馆
推呀 丹尼尔 用力推! 用尽全力推! 加油!
Push, Daniel. Give it all you've got, kid. Push!
好了 发动了 快快 跳进来!
Okay, we've got it. Come on. Get in, hurry up.
你又办到啦 好极了!
We did it again. Way to go!
醒来
Daniel, wake up.
看看右舷方向 总算来到乐园了!
Look off the starboard bow. Paradise at last.
我们到了
We made it.
来吧
Come on.
就是这里
This is it.
这里是终点站
This is the end of the line.
还用你说
You're telling me.
来吧 开始行动
Come on. All hands on deck.
我们得在车子下沉前 把行李拿光
We've got to get this thing unloaded before it sinks.
看看那些棕榈树! 哇塞! 你知道这代表什么吗?
Look at those palm trees! Damn, do you know what that means?
小心会有椰子掉下来
Yeah, watch out for falling coconuts.
-聪明鬼 再没有纽沃的冬天啦! -妈 我喜欢冬天
-Wise guy. No more Newark winters. -I like winters.
你喜欢喉咙痛? 冰冷的脚趾头?
Oh, you like sore throats? You like frozen toes?
我不喜欢烟雾
I don't like smog.
-我说过这里有游泳池了没? -妈 你说过100次了
-Did I tell you about the pool here? -About 100 times.
好吧 再说第101次
Okay, so make it 101.
睁开眼睛 我亲爱的儿子 这是伊甸园哪!
Open your eyes, my darling son. This is the Garden of Eden.
来 我们住20号公寓 知道吧?
Come on. Listen, we're in apartment 20, okay?
要上楼
One flight up.
-你还好吧? -我没事 别担心
-Are you okay? -Don't worry about it.
-我扶你 -谢啦
-Let me help you up. -Thanks.
你没事? 我不该那么做的 别担心
I shouldn't have done that. It was stupid.
你一定是刚搬进20号公寓的人
You must be the new people in 20, right?
我想是吧
Yeah, I guess so.
-佛莱迪菲南德斯 17号公寓 -丹尼尔拉罗素
-Freddy Fernandez, apartment 17. -Daniel LaRusso.
你好 我帮你拿
How you doing? Let me help.
-不必 很重的 -我来拿 没关系
-No, it's fine. It's heavy, man. -I got it.
-你从哪里来? -纽泽西州
-Where are you from? -New Jersey.
你来这里做什么?
What are you doing out here?
我妈在这里的公司找到工作
My mom got a job with some company out here. Rocket Computers.
火箭 电脑 未来航班 我不知道
Flight of the Future. I don't know.
-没听过 -很有发展的
-I never heard of it. -It's up and coming.
-这就是你们这里唯一的游泳池? -对 就是那个 嘿 你那是空手道吗?
-Is this the only pool you've got? -That's it. What was that, karate?
-是的 -你练了很久?
-Yeah. -Have you been doing it long?
-一阵子 -用过吗?
-Yeah, a while. -Did you ever use it?
-几次 -用来打架一定不错吧?
-A couple of times. -I bet you could kick some ass.
我有空也想学学 你可以教我
I'd like to learn that. Maybe you could teach me.
-当然 随时都可以 -太好了
-Sure. That's cool. Anytime. -Great.
这地方很烂 你该回到纽泽西去的
This place is a dump. You should go back to New Jersey.
你怎知道我从泽西来?
How did you know where I was from?
因为我是从纽泽西来 我可以看得出来
'Cause I'm from New Jersey. I got a nose for my own.
-从哪里? -帕斯潘尼
-Well what part? -Parsippany.
-当初真不该离开 -我有个路易叔叔就是帕斯潘尼人
-I never should've left. -My Uncle Louie's from Parsippany.
-路易凡提尼? -路易拉罗素
-Louie Martini? -Louie LaRusso.
路易拉罗素 不认识
Louie LaRusso? Don't know him.
嗨 小狗
Hey, pup.
你怎么样? 很渴吗?
How you doing? You thirsty?
-她是疯子 -什么?
-She's crazy. -What?
-她脑筋不太正常 -她很好啊
-She's not playing with a full deck. -She's nice.
-你明天要做什么? -我不知道 没事吧
-What are you doing tomorrow? -I don't know. I guess nothing.
我们有个海滩派对 有点像告别夏天的 你想来吗?
We're having a beach party. Want to come?
-当然 那太棒了 -好 我明天来接你
-Sure, that's cool. -I'll come get you in the morning.
好 这里就是20号公寓
Here's apartment 20.
-这里? -我放在这里罗?
-Is it? -Should I leave this here?
-好 谢谢你帮忙 -没问题
-Yeah, thanks for the help. -No problem.
-很高兴认识你 -我也是 -保重 明天见 -好
-Nice meeting you. -Sure -Take care. See you tomorrow morning. -All right
别跟我提游泳池 我明天一大早就打电话去问
Don't say anything about the pool. I'll call first thing in the morning.
你跟那个老女人说我们从哪来了?
Did you tell that old lady where we were from?
对啊 她会让你想起泰西婶婶吧?
Yes. Didn't she remind you of Aunt Tessy?
-泰西婶婶? 比较像路易叔叔 -我真觉得我们在这里会过得很快乐
-More like Uncle Louie. -I really think we're going to do good here.
告诉你 丹尼尔 我对这里的感觉很好
I have a very positive feeling. I'm telling you, Daniel.
我知道一定会顺利的 水龙头坏了
I just know it's going to work. The faucet's broken.
仲介小姐说有个修理工住在这里 你能不能去找他?
The real estate lady said there's a fix -it guy. See if you can find him.
那是干嘛的?
What's that for?
-这个? 要给路易叔叔的小狗 -它很可爱
-Uncle Louie's dog. -He's cute.
-妈 有人邀请我明天去一个派对 好呀 我就说吧?
-I got invited to a party tomorrow. -Great. You see?
-我知道 但你要我帮你整理东西 -我可不记得说过这件事
-But you wanted me to help you unpack. -I don't remember saying that.
好极了 我一定把你跟其他人弄混了
I must have had you mixed up with somebody else.
妈 谢啦
Thanks, Ma.
你知道修理工人在哪吗?
Could you tell me where the maintenance guy is?
嗨 小子 给你喝
Hey, pup.
你走进那边 左转 不要走远…
You go in through there, turn left, not too far...
然后右转 进去 你会看到他在左边
... then right, go inside, and you'll find him on the left.
所以我先右转再左转
So I go right then left?
不对 左 然后右 然后左边的里面
No, left then right, then inside on the left.
哈罗?
Hello?
你是修理工吗?
Are you the maintenance man?
我们刚搬进20号公寓
We're the new people in apartment 20.
我们的水龙头漏水了
The faucet's really leaking there.
你能来修吗?
Could you come fix it?
我能去告诉我妈何时吗?
Can I tell my mom when?
什么何时?
When what?
你何时来修水龙头
When you're going to fix the faucet.
以后
After.
在什么以后?
After what?
以后!
After after!
请把球还我好吗? 谢谢
Could we have the ball, please?
他很不错
Pretty good.
卖弄
Show -off.
拜 嗨 等等!
Sorry. Hey, wait up.
-穿蓝衣的金发女孩是谁? --山庄的
-Who's that blonde in the blue? -The hills.
-什么是山庄的? -有钱人
-What's the hills? -Rich.
-喂 丹尼尔 -什么?
-hey, Daniel -What?
-我觉得那个金发女孩在看你 -是哦
-I think the blonde is looking at you. -Yeah, right.
-我说真的啦 我觉得她喜欢你喔 -这也不能怪她 对吧 佛莱迪?
-I think she has the hots for you. -Who could blame her?
-那你为什么不去搭讪? -不要 我在吃东西
-Why don't you make a move? -No, I'm eating, man.
-你怎么还能想到吃? 去搭讪啦 -我饿呀
-How can you think about eating? -I'm hungry.
-或许他老家那边的人都没胆子 -我有胆子
-Maybe they ain't got no moves in Jersey. -I got moves where I come from.
-我们那边的人比这里更有胆 -是吗?
-We've got more moves back there than here, I'll tell you that much. -Yeah?
做来看看
Let's see 'em.
来吧 伙计 去追她
Come on, buddy. Go get her.
-好 我去了 -去追她
-I'm going. -Go
我在走了啦
I'm going.
-你掉了什么吗? -希望我们没吵到你
-Lose something? -I hope we're not bothering you.
你怎么玩球的?
Hey, how do you juggle?
很简单 我先从膝盖开始 你先踢一下
It's pretty easy. You start on the knee. You just go one.
一次一下 一 然后试踢两下 一 二
One at a time. Then you try two. One, two.
你试试 三 四 试试看 把脚抬高 一 对啦!
And then three and four. Try it. Just bring your leg up. Good!
-看哪! 真了不起! -啤酒时间到! 谁要烫手的?
-That was awesome! -Brew time. Who's for a warm one?
不 谢了
No, I pass.
你开什么玩笑? 你是最糟的
Who are you kidding? You're the ace degenerate.
不 最烂的! 明早8点 我就升级了 我还有一年的时间可以努力
Ex -degenerate. Tomorrow I'm a senior. I've got one year to make it all work.
-我就是要这样 要成功 一切 怎样? -好耶 老兄
-And that's what I'm gonna do. Make it work, all of it.-That right.
强尼 你一定是领导流行的人 看起来大家都有新鲜事做
You must be a trendsetter, Johnny. Everyone's doing something new.
往右边看一下
Take a right. Check it out.
-强尼 算了吧 已经是历史了 -谁说的?
-Forget it, man. It's ancient history. -Who told you, man?
-我以为他们分手了 -她分了 他可没有
-I thought they broke up. -She did, he didn't.
来 再试一次
Come on, try it.
看好喔
Watch this.
我去拣 马上回来
I'll get it. I'll be right back.
-艾莉 我有话跟你说 -别烦我
-Ali, I want to talk to you. -Leave me alone.
我们该谈的都谈过了 对吧? 我不想谈
We've been over all this. I don't want to talk.
哦 我要跟你说话 不行吗?
I want to talk to you, all right?
-你有什么问题? -你为什么不离开?
-What is your problem? -Just get out of here.
-好 这样就解决一切问题了 -收音机还我
-That won't solve anything. -Give me my radio.
还我收音机!
I said, give me my radio.
-那你答应跟我说话? -好 先还我收音机
-You promise you'll talk to me? -Yes, give me my radio.
-你摔坏我的收音机了? -对
-You just broke my radio! -Yeah.
别碰 呆子 你聋子吗?
Don't touch it, punk.
-喂 怎么回事 -你要?
-What's going on? -You want it?
-给你! -好耶!
-Get it! -All right!
打呀 丹尼尔
强尼 住手!
Johnny, stop it.
-住手! -我什么也没做
-Stop it. -I didn't do anything.
你是个大人物?
You're a big man now, huh?
喂 是你开头的 我只是想跟你说话而已
You started this. I just wanted to talk.
-那就放开他 我们去说话 -这谎话我好像听过吧?
-Leave him alone and we'll talk. -Where did I hear that before?
你呢 大英雄? 够了吗?
How about you, hero? Had enough?
-好 现在我们平手了 -别心软
-Now we're even. -No mercy, man.
放开我! 你为什么不打我?
Why don't you hit me?
-是你的错 -不是我的错
-It's your fault! -It's not.
-都是你的错! -都是你的
-It's your fault. -Ever think it's yours?
你为什么总是爱打架?
Why do you always have to fight?
狗屁 大家上车
Bullshit. Get on your bikes, guys.
佛莱迪 你还真会找人做朋友嘛
You sure pick cool people to be friends with.
你哪里找来这个人的?
Where'd you find this guy?
我们走吧 他不会有事的
Come on, let's go. He'll be all right.
-你没事吧? -别管我
-Are you okay? -Just leave me alone.
-我来帮你 -别管我 我没事
-I'll help you. -Leave me alone. I'm okay.
来吧 艾莉 我们走 让他独自一人比较好
Come on, Ali. Let's go. It's better if you leave him alone.
走吧
Come on, let's go.
丹尼尔
Daniel!
-嗨 妈 -派对怎么样? -还好
-How was the party? -It was okay.
不会只是还好吧 我可没听到你回家
Must have been more than okay. I didn't hear you come in.
-交到朋友了? -有一些
-Any friend material? -Some. I got to go.
-我要走了 -先坐下吃东西
-Eat first. -I'm not hungry.
-不 我不饿 -你要有体力才会迷人 -我很好 我有体力
-You need energy to be charming. -I'm fine, I got energy.
拜托啦 把眼镜拿掉
Do me a favour. Take off the glasses.
-为什么? -因为我要你拿掉
-Why? -Because I asked you to.
-这是加州 这样才流行… -拿掉眼镜 我要看你的棕色眼睛
-It's California. It's the look. -I want to see your baby browns.
-妈 别这样说啦 -你在嗑东西吗?
-Come on with the baby browns. -Are you on something?
-对啦 嗑果汁… -为什么要遮住眼睛?
-I'm on Minute Maid. -Why hide your eyes?
-我没有遮住眼睛 -那就把眼镜拿掉!
-I'm not. -Take off the glasses.
现在
Now!
噢 我的天 怎么回事?
My God! How did that happen?
我骑脚踏车撞到路边受伤了 我戴眼镜因为我不想让你担心
I hit a kerb with my bike. I wore the glasses so you wouldn't worry.
-糟得… -别碰!
-It looks worse than it feels. -Don't do that.
-会更严重的 -你看得见吗? 你要留在家里?
-It doesn't hurt. -Can you see? You want to stay home?
我要走
I've got to go.
本建筑献给真理 自由 宽容
1969年四月金色西部的原住民捐赠
-嗨 佛莱迪 你好吗? -嗨 空手道小子
-Hey, you guys, Freddy, how you doing? -Hey, the karate kid.
秀两下吧
Let's see the moves.
-他只知道怎样被人揍 -这我已经知道啦
-He knows how to get his butt kicked. -I already know that move.
继续打球吧
Let's get out of here.
接住!
Hey, think fast.
-嗨 -你好吗?
-Hi. -Hi, how are you doing?
-你的眼睛 -别担心 相信我 只是看起来比较严重而已
-Your eye. -It looks worse than it feels. Believe me.
希望如此
I hope so.
对了 我一直没机会谢谢你
I never got a chance to thank you.
小事一桩 真遗憾你的收音机坏了
That was nothing. I'm just sorry about your radio.
我对你的眼睛才遗憾呢
I'm more sorry about your eye.
我猜你真该就让他拿去的
You should've just given it to him.
为什么? 那又不是他的?
Why? It wasn't his, right?
-嗯 不是他的 -看吧 我们想法差不多
-Yeah, it wasn't his. -We think alike already.
你知道我们还有哪里相像?
You know what else we do alike?
哇 你有练习过
You've been practicing.
-啦啦队员 这里集合 -我得走了
-Cheerleaders, over here. -I've got to go.
-再见 -好 拜拜
-I'll see you. -'Bye.
-拜拜 你有名字吗? -艾莉 有个"艾"字
-Hey, have you got a name? -Ali with an "i."
-你的名字呢? -丹尼尔 有个"尔"字
-What's your name? -Daniel with an "I."
待会见
I'll see you later.
当然
Definitely.
冲 打 赢! 触地得分!
加油
Get him, Bobby.
我来接
Right now
你去哪?
Where are you?
玩得不错吧?
Have a nice trip?
教练 看看他对巴比怎么了!
Look what he's doing to Bobby.
不准打我! 我要把你的脸撕下来!
Nobody hits me. I'm going to kill him.
-出去! 这个队里不准有暴力 -他先打我的!
-None of that on this team! -He hooked me!
我叫你出去!
I said out of here!
看什么看? 回去练习 快点!
Back to it. Let's go.
-这学校烂死了! -我叫你出去!
-This school sucks! It sucks. -I said you get that here
二 三 四…
52, 53, 54...
五 六 七
55, 56, 57...
-修理水龙头 -好 请进
-Fix faucet. -Come on in.
厨房那个
It's the kitchen one.
一 二 三…
1, 2, 3...
空手道
Karate.
-对 五 六 -很好
-Yeah, 5, 6... -Very good.
-跟书学? -对 以前我住纽沃时在YMCA学过几个月
-Learn from book? -And a few months at the Y in Newark.
九 十…
9, 10...
…十一 十二 十三…
... 11, 12, 13...
眼睛怎么回事?
What happened to eye?
从脚踏车上跌下来了
I fell off my bike.
没伤到手算你走运
Lucky no hurt hand.
-嗨 艾莉有个"艾" 你好吗? -好
-Ali with an "i." How are you doing? -Good.
-今天不怎么饿嘛 -还好
-Not too hungry today? -Not really.
来吃点派 我自己做的
Have some pie, I made it myself.
-你还喜欢河谷区吗? -满无聊的
-How do you like the valley? -It hasn't been dull.
纽沃无聊吗?
Was Newark dull?
你怎知道我从那里来?
How did you know I was from there?
-我问过了 -真的?
-I asked. -Oh, really?
-你跟谁坐? -可以的话 跟你坐
-Are you sitting with anybody? -With you, if it's okay.
-好呀 你要牛奶吗? -好 谢谢
-Sounds great to me. Want some milk? -Thanks.
-足球队选拔的事真遗憾 -那叫做倒霉
-Sorry about the soccer tryouts. -Those are the breaks.
记得在海滩跟我起冲突的那个男生?
Remember that guy you had trouble with on the beach?
-空手道王吗? -他是我前任男朋友
-Yeah, King Karate? -He's my ex -boyfriend.
能知道真好 什么?
That's good to know. What?
没错 我知道…
Yeah, you're right. I know.
-你做什么? -脑中有个声音
-What are you doing? -It's this little voice...
告诉我我一定是呆瓜 才会跟你说话
... telling me I've got to be nuts to be talking to you.
-2美金50分 -等等 一起付
-That'll be $2.50. -For both.
-3美金75分 -反正已经没关系了
-$3.75. -It doesn't matter, anyway.
-为什么? -因为已经结束了 -结束了?
-Why's that? -Because it's over.
-等等 结束多久? -好几周了
-Wait. How over? -Weeks.
几周 一周? 五周? 几个礼拜才是"好几周"?
One week, five weeks? How many weeks is "weeks"?
空手道
-这道场里没有恐惧 对不对? -没 老师!
-Fear does not exist in this dojo. Does it? -No, Sensei!
-这道场里没有痛苦 对不对? -没 老师!
-Pain does not exist in this dojo. Does it? -No, Sensei!
-这道场里没有失败 对不对? -没 老师!
-Defeat doesn't exist in this dojo. Does it? -No, Sensei!
-这道场里没有恐惧 对不对? -没 老师!
-Fear does not exist in this dojo. Does it? -No, Sensei!
-这道场里没有痛苦 对不对? -没 老师!
-Pain does not exist in this dojo. Does it? -No, Sensei!
-这道场里没有失败 对不对? -没 老师!
-Defeat doesn't exist in this dojo. Does it? -No, Sensei!
预备!
Prepare.
-我们来这里学什么? -先生 来学抵御!
-What do we study here? -The way of the fist, sir!
-抵御是什么? -攻击迅速 用力 不心软 先生!
-And what is that way? -Strike first, strike hard, no mercy!
-我听不见! -攻击迅速 用力 不心软 先生!
-I can't hear you. -Strike first, strike hard, no mercy!
-劳伦斯先生 -是的 先生
-Mr. Lawrence. -Yes, Sensei.
带大家做暖身运动
Warm them up.
攻击姿势!
Fighting positions. Jab punch.
拳击 预备!
Ready.
东方快车 -餐厅
-你猜怎么? -怎么? -我要被培训成一位主管喔
-Guess what. -What? -I'm going to be trained as a manager.
-棒吧? -对
-Isn't that great?
他们有个课程 一周两个晚上
The programme's two nights a week.
只要有空位 就可以参加 福利呢 简直是我在电脑业里得不到的
As soon as a spot opens up, I'm in. The benefits are great.
他们什么都付
They pay for everything.
妈 太棒了
That's great.
-丹尼尔 怎么回事? -没事
-What's the matter, Daniel? -Nothing.
记得你刚到乡下过夏天时…你很不喜欢 因为你没有朋友?
Remember when you went to the country and hated it 'cause you had no friends?
结果呢?
What happened?
我得了野葛过敏
I got poison ivy.
你遇见了凯文和凯尼 他们成为你最要好的朋友
You met Kevin and Kenny, who became your best friends in the world.
你一定要再努力点
You've got to give it a try.
我知道这很难
I know it's hard.
但我们绝不退缩 对吧?
We're not quitters, are we?
我想是的
I guess not.
-空手道那里怎样? -烂透了
-What's with the karate place? -It sucks.
那好 反正我们大概也负担不起
Good. We couldn't afford it anyway.
交女朋友的状况如何?
And the girl situation?
-还可以 -只是还可以?
-It's okay. -Just okay?
我看起来倒像是整个世界都变金了
To me it looks like the whole world turned blonde.
你有喜欢的人了吗?
You got your eye on anybody?
很可爱?
Cute?
不 不是可爱
Not cute.
-我是说 她比可爱还好看 -但她是金发对吧?
-She's beyond cute. -But she's blonde, right?
-她有金发 -露西欧 快走 他们来了
-She's got blonde hair. -Lucille, let's go, here they come.
-她跟裘蒂一样漂亮? -她一下就把裘蒂给比下去了
-Is she as pretty as Judy? -She buries Judy in a second.
她把裘蒂比下去?
She buries Judy?
你等等再告诉我 我爱你 回家路上骑车要小心
Tell me about it later. I love you. Careful how you ride home.
笑容 她的笑容真甜 她非常聪明
She's got an excellent smile. She's really smart.
我不知道 我会说她很漂亮 我觉得她很漂亮
I'd say she's beautiful. I think she's beautiful.
我觉得她与众不同
I think she's something else.
她很辣 绝对够辣
She's hot. Definitely hot.
-想找去纽沃的捷径吗? -不 他想学空手道
-Looking for a shortcut to Newark? -He wants to learn karate.
这是你的第一课 如何摔倒 你们干什么? 别去想痛苦
Here's the first lesson How to take a fall. Don't think about the pain.
可恶的脚踏车 我恨这脚踏车
Damn bike! I hate this bike!
我恨这他妈的脚踏车! 笨车!
I hate this frigging bike! Stupid bike!
-丹尼尔 怎么回事? 为什么你把脚踏车丢掉? -没事
-What's the matter? Why did you throw your bike away?
-因为我想丢 -我跟你说话时看着我
-Because I felt like it. -Look at me when I'm talking to you.
噢 我的天!
My God!
说说到底怎么回事? 别告诉我又出了脚踏车意外
Tell me what's going on. Don't say another bike accident.
-你想听什么 妈? -实话
-What do you want to hear? -The truth.
不 你不想 你只想听这个地方有多好
No, all you want to hear is how great it is here.
或许对你是如此 但对我烂透了! 我恨这个地方!
Maybe for you, but it sucks for me. I hate this place!
我只想回家! 为什么我们不能回家!
I hate it, I want to go home! Why can't we just go back home?
-听我说 -什么?
-Listen to me. -What?
除非你告诉我怎么回事 否则我帮不上忙
I cannot help you unless you tell me what's wrong.
我非学空手道不可 就这样!
I've got to take karate.
-你学过呀 -不 不是在YMCA 要在好学校
-You took karate. -Not at the Y, at a good school.
-打架并不能解决问题 -棕榈树也不能
-Fighting doesn't solve anything. -Neither does palm trees.
这样说不公平
That's not fair.
没事先问过我就跑来这里 难道就很公平?
It wasn't fair coming out here without asking me.
你说得对
You're right.
我该问问你的
I should've asked.
我只想回家 如此而已 我不懂这里的规则
I just want to go home. I don't understand the rules here.
我们来想办法看看能不能 一起找出这里的规则 好不好?
Let's see if we can figure out the rules together.
-你的脚踏车怎么办? -搭公车安全多了
-What about your bike? -It's safer taking the bus.
为什么我们不能回家 把这地方忘掉?
Why can't we just go home and forget this place?
-我会告诉你他说的每句话 -最好这样
-I'll tell you everything he said. -You'd better.
嗨 你好吗?
How are you?
-你的额头怎么啦? -糟透了 长了个超大的青春痘
-What happened to your forehead? -It's terrible. A gigantic runaway zit.
真恶心 -
That's gross.
丹尼尔 这是苏珊 到底发生了什么事?
Daniel, this is Susan. What really happened?
我骑车摔了 但我没事
I got in a bike accident.
你骑什么车? 本田? 铃木?
What kind of bike do you have? A Honda? Suzuki?
不 是宫城涡轮
It's a Miyagi Turbo.
-真的? -真的?
-Yeah? -Oh, really?
-我们要去打电动玩具 你要一起来吗? -当然 好极了
-We're going to the arcade. Want to come? -Sounds great.
你一定要看看这个新游戏 我弄给你看
There's this new game I want to show you.
我突然想起来了 我忘了一个东西 我晚点再去找你们
I forgot something. I'll catch up with you guys in a minute.
-你不需要逃走 -我没有逃走
-Don't run away. -I'm not running away from anything.
-总该有个对策 -你用你的方式去应付 我用我的方式 我要走了
-We've got to deal with this. -I'll deal with it my own way.
-丹尼尔… -别管我!
-Daniel... -Get off my case!
你修了我的脚踏车?
Did you fix my bike?
-谢谢 --不客气
-Thank you. -You're welcome.
我真的很感激
I really appreciate that.
那些是真的树吗?
Are those real trees?
你想看就进来
You like see, come inside.
谢谢
Thanks.
怎么长得这么小?
How did they get so small?
我修剪的
I train.
这里剪一点 那里修一下
Clip here, tie there.
你在哪学的? 日本吗?
Did you learn this in Japan?
冲绳
Okinawa.
那是哪里?
Where's that?
我的国家
My country.
中国 这里
China here.
日本 这里
Japan here.
冲绳 这里
Okinawa here.
你去学校学的吗?
Did you go to school for this?
父亲教的
Father teach.
他是园丁?
Was he a gardener?
渔夫
Fisherman.
渔夫?
A fisherman.
真漂亮
These are really beautiful.
来 你试试
Come, you try.
我不知道该怎么做
I don't know how to do this stuff.
-坐下不 -我会弄砸的 我不想把它弄砸
-Sit down. -I may mess it up or something.
闭上眼睛
Close eyes.
信任
Trust.
专心
Concentrate.
只想树
Think only tree.
想像一幅图画 连一针一叶都不忽略
Make a perfect picture down to last pine needle.
澄清你的心灵 除了树之外什么都不想
Wipe your mind clean. Everything but the tree.
世界上什么都没有
Nothing exists in whole world...
只有树
... only tree.
好了吗?
You got it?
睁开眼睛
Open eyes.
记得那图?
Remember picture?
记得
Yeah.
照那图来剪
Make like picture.
只要信任那图
Just trust the picture.
但我怎么知道我的图是对的?
How do I know my picture's the right one?
如果来自你内心 一定是对的
If come from inside you, always the right one.
嗨
Hi.
嘿 妈 进来吧
Hi, Ma, come on in.
-你修好脚踏车了 -不 宫城先生修好的
-You fixed your bike. -Mr. Miyagi fixed it.
哇 太棒了 谢谢你
Great, thank you.
-我们该给你多少钱? -不用钱
-How much do we owe you? -No, please.
我的荣幸
My pleasure.
那真好
That's very nice.
哈罗 小冠军
Hi, champ.
嗨
Hey.
-你在做什么? -我在修剪我的小树
-What are you doing? -I'm trimming my baby tree.
盆栽树
Bonsai tree.
盆栽
Bonsai.
好漂亮
They're beautiful.
宫城先生在冲绳学的 他从那里来
Mr. Miyagi learned it in Okinawa. That's where he's from.
真的?
Really?
好精致
They're so delicate.
给我?
For me?
不 我不能收
No, I couldn't.
请收下 别让我难过
Please, hurt feelings.
你真好 谢谢
That's very nice, thank you.
-不客气 -我知道该放哪里
-Welcome. -I know just where it will go.
走吧 不早了
Come on, it's getting late.
-好 我在过半小时就上去 -不 我们现在就走 明天要上学
-I'll be up in a half hour. -No, now. School tomorrow.
-真是谢谢你 -不客气
-Thank you for everything. -You're welcome.
别忘了树
Don't forget tree.
要练习
Must practice.
谢谢
Thank you.
-莎哟娜拉 -莎哟娜拉
-Sayonara. -Sayonara.
-晚安 -再次谢谢你 再见
-Goodnight. -Thanks again. See you.
他把最棒的给我了 他真的好特别
Ma, he gave you the nicest one. This guy is something else.
你看到他把我脚踏车修好了 这人真棒
You saw what he did to my bike. This guy is great.
-丹尼尔桑 万圣节快乐 喜欢吗? -嗯 不错
-Happy Halloween. You like? -Yeah, that's nice.
学校今天都好? 很多事发生
Passed school today. Lots happening.
怎么回事? 你不去?
What's the matter? You're not going?
没
No.
为什么?
How come?
我不太喜欢跳舞
I'm not into dancing that much.
反正我也不想跳
I don't feel like it, anyway.
丹尼尔桑 你太孤僻了 不好
You're too much by self. Not good.
我没有孤僻
I'm not by myself.
我跟你在一起
I'm with you.
要做蜂蜜 小蜜蜂需要新鲜花朵 不是老梅子
To make honey, young bee need young flower, not old prune.
反正我也没有服装
I don't have a costume, anyway.
有服装
If have costume...
你就去?
... you go?
如果我能变隐形人的话 或许吧
If I went as the Invisible Man.
隐形人"?
Invisible Man?
你知道 就是没人能看见我
You know, so no one would see me.
嗨 那是丹尼尔
There's Daniel.
-哪里? -那个淋浴室
-Where? -In the shower.
-你怎么知道? -我就是知道
-How do you know? -I just know.
借我?
May I?
-不晓得她喜欢他哪一点 -她一定有问题
-I don't know what she sees in him. -She must be into fungus.
救我! 我的花需要水!
Help me, my flower needs water.
你来对地方了 陌生人
You've come to the right place, stranger.
-我从没有在浴室里跳过舞 -我一个朋友做的 好有趣
-I've never danced in a shower. -A friend of mine made this for me.
很棒吧?
Isn't it great?
所以 你都躲到哪去啦?
Where have you been hiding?
我没有躲起来
I haven't been hiding.
-我都没看到你 -你在找我?
-I haven't seen you around. -You been looking?
-算是吧 -算是?
-Sort of. -Sort of?
我以为你还在生我的气
I thought you were still angry with me.
-为什么? -因为我上次见到你时说的话
-Why? -Because of what I said last time I saw you.
不 我想过很多了
I've been thinking a lot about that.
我知道 但我该学学管自己的事就好
I should learn to mind my own business.
不 我想你说要面对问题是对的 我也这么觉得
No, I think you're right about facing things. I feel the same way.
我只是忘记了
I just kind of forgot for a while.
-谢谢你提醒了我 -不客气
-Thanks for reminding me. -You're welcome.
他认为他可以对别人为所欲为
He thinks he can do whatever he wants to people.
-谁? -强尼
-Who? -Johnny.
我真希望有人能对他以牙还牙
I'd love to see him get some of his own medicine.
哦 恶会有恶报的
What goes around comes around.
-我希望到时候我可以在场 -我也是
-I'd love to be there when it does. -Me, too.
你想不想出去?
You want to go outside?
你说服我了
You talked me into it.
-看看这只鸡 他疯了! -这家伙用的是真蛋
-That chicken is wild! -That guy's using real eggs!
他真厉害
He's great!
不!
No!
强尼
Johnny!
强尼!
-卷好麻烟没? -再等一下
-Got that number rolled? -In a minute.
-我去叫他们 快 -好
-I'm going to get the guys. -Hurry up.
干!
Shit!
嘿 老兄 走开!
Move, man!
嘿 强尼 怎么了?
Johnny, what's up?
别挡路! 小心!
Get out of my way!
-丹尼尔 怎么了? -报应来啦
-What's wrong? -It's coming around.
起来!
Get up!
别挡路!
Get out of my way!
你他妈的在做什么?
What the hell are you doing?
快走开!
Get out of the way!
他过不去的
You ain't going nowhere.
抓到他了
你这个懦弱鬼
You little wimp!
你就是忍不住 对吧 懦弱鬼?
You couldn't leave well enough alone, could you, little twerp?
不 你就是要惹我们 现在该你尝苦头了
No, you had to push it. Well, now you're gonna pay!
你要去哪里?
Where are you going, sweetheart?
怎么啦? 想踢强尼吗?
How about a front kick, Johnny?
拉他起来
Get him up.
-别管他了 他也受够了 -闭嘴 巴比!
-He's had enough. -Shut up!
-看看他 连站都站不起来了 -那又怎样? 那又不代表什么
-He can't even stand up. -That don't mean squat.
-强尼 放了他 打够了 -我来决定打够他了没
-Johnny, he's had enough. -I'll decide when he's had enough.
你到底怎么回事?
What's wrong with you, Johnny?
-对敌人不可以心软 对吧? -对
-An enemy deserves no mercy. -Right!
你疯了!
You're crazy, man!
强尼 巴比 打他!
Get him!
丹尼尔桑
Daniel -san.
来
Come.
你安全了
丹 放在头上
Leave on.
-臭死了 这什么东西? -闻起来臭 疗效很好
-It stinks. What is it? -Smell bad, heal good.
-那个蜘蛛人呢? -谁?
-Where did Spider -Man go? -Who?
那个救了我的人 他到哪去了?
The guy who bailed me out. Where'd he go?
什么 你?
What, you?
-不可能 -为什么不可能?
-No way. -Why "no way"?
-因为… -因为老头子?
-Because... -Because, old man?
喝茶
Have tea.
会好些
Feel better.
你怎么没告诉我?
Why didn't you tell me?
-告诉你什么? -你会空手道
-Tell you what? -That you do karate.
-你没问 -你在哪学的?
-You never ask. -Where'd you learn it?
父亲
Father.
我以为他是渔夫
I thought he was a fisherman.
在冲绳 所有宫城都会两件事
In Okinawa, all Miyagi know two things:
捕鱼和空手道
Fish and karate.
空手道来自中国 16世纪
Karate come from China, 16th century.
称为"唐" "手"
Called "te, " hand.
很久以后
Much later...
宫城祖先称为"空手道" "空手"
... Miyagi ancestors call "karate, " empty hand.
我一直以为那是从佛教寺庙那里来的
I always thought it came from Buddhist temples.
你电视看多了
You, too much TV.
我妈也这么说
That's what my mother tells me.
-你教过谁吗? -没
-Have you ever taught anyone? -No.
你会教吗?
Would you?
-要看 -看什么?
-It depend. -On what?
看原因
Reason.
复仇如何?
How's revenge?
丹尼尔桑 你这么想复仇 不如先挖好两个坟墓
You look for revenge that way, start by digging two graves.
至少我有伴 对吧?
At least I'd have company, right?
打架不是解决问题的办法
Fighting always last answer to problem.
不想冒犯你 宫城先生 但我认为你不了解我的问题
Mr. Miyagi, I don't think you understand my problem.
宫城先生完全了解问题
Miyagi understand problem perfect.
你的朋友都是空手道学生?
Your friend all karate student?
"朋友"? 是哦 那些人
Friends? Yeah, those guys.
问题在於态度
Problem attitude.
不 问题在於我每隔一天就被人揍
The problem is I keep getting my ass kicked.
因为那些人态度恶劣
Because boys have bad attitude.
空手道只是为了抵R
Karate for defence only.
那些人可不是这样学的
That's not what these guys are taught.
看得出来
I can see.
没有坏学生 只有坏老师
No such thing bad student, only bad teacher.
老师教 学生做
Teacher say, student do.
好 那就解决我的问题了
Great, that solves everything.
我只要去学校 跟老师讨论这事就好 没问题
I'll go to the school and straighten it out with the teacher.
这主意不错
Now use head for something other than target.
-我是开玩笑的 -为什么开玩笑?
-I was only kidding. -Why kidding?
因为如果我去那里 我会被揍死
I get killed if I show up there.
反正你总会被揍死
Get killed anyway.
你会跟我去吗?
Would you go with me?
不 不行
No, I can't.
为什么? 你说那是好主意不是吗?
Why? You said it was a good idea.
对你来说是个好主意
For you, good idea.
对我 不要干涉才好
For me, good idea no get involved.
但你已经干涉…
But you're already involved.
-非常抱歉 -什么?
-Very sorry. -What?
不谢你哦
Thanks for nothing then.
好像我问题还不够多似的
Like I didn't have enough problems already.
现在我还得为你的事负责 老兄 请你别再帮我了
Now I've got to carry your weight, too. Don't do me any more favours.
-丹尼尔桑? -什么?
-Daniel -san. -What?
好 我去
Okay, I go.
-太棒了 宫城先生 这太棒了 -宫城
-Excellent, Mr. Miyagi. -Miyagi.
宫城
Miyagi.
你是什么带的?
What kind of belt do you have?
帆布的
Canvas.
你喜欢?
You like?
-洁西潘尼百货 3美金98分 -我不是问那种皮带
-J.C. Penney. $3.98. -I hadn't mean that belt
我是指…
I meant...
在冲绳 皮带表示 不需要绳子来绑紧裤子
In Okinawa a belt means no need rope hold up pants.
真好笑
That's funny.
-丹尼尔桑 -什么?
-Daniel -san. -What?
空手道在这里
Karate here.
空手道从不在这里
Karate never here.
你懂?
You understand?
我想是
I think so.
晚安 丹尼尔桑
Goodnight, Daniel -san.
晚安 宫城 宫城先生
Goodnight, Mr. Miyagi. Miyagi!
明天一早?
Tomorrow morning?
10点
10:00.
谢谢你把我从朋友那里救出来
Thanks for helping me out with my friends out there.
-早安 宫城先生 -早安 丹尼尔桑 你今早觉得怎样?
-Good morning, Mr. Miyagi. -How do you feel?
-有点酸痛 -你会开车?
-A little sore. -You know how drive?
对啊 我会
Yeah, I do.
-我开得不好 宫城先生 -我也不好
-No, I'm not very good at it. -Me neither.
我也没有驾照
I don't have a licence.
我也没有
Me neither.
那我想这样就没问题了
I guess it's okay then.
杀!
12月19日报名参加!
18届全谷区空手道冠军赛
你在打架中失神 你就死定了
You lose concentration in a fight and you're dead meat!
-是 老师 -什么?
-Yes, Sensei. -What?
是 老师!
Yes, Sensei!
起来
Get up!
去用指节做60下伏地挺身
Give me 60 pushups on your knuckles.
搏斗!
Combat!
布朗 罗伯森
Brown. Robertson.
准备!
On guard.
点数 前踢
Point. Round kick.
你在看哪里? 打败他!
What are you looking at? Finish him!
回来
Return.
预备
Prepare.
我们不是来训练心软的 心软是弱者的行为
We do not train to be merciful, here. Mercy is for the weak.
这里 路上 或在竞赛中
Here, on the street, in competition...
跟你对抗的就是敌人
... a man confronts you, he is the enemy.
对敌人不可以心软 劳伦斯先生 你有什么问题?
An enemy deserves no mercy. What is the problem, Mr. Lawrence?
走吧 算了
Come on, let's forget this.
等等 还没
Wait, not yet.
各位 我们有客人 在我身后排好
Class, we have visitors. Fall in behind me.
我听说你昨晚击倒了我的几个学生
I hear you jumped some of my students last night.
恐怕你弄错了
Afraid the facts mixed up.
你说劳伦斯先生是骗子吗?
Are you calling him a liar?
没说谁是什么
No call no one nothing.
老头子 你来这里做什么?
What are you here for, old man?
请你放这孩子一马
Come ask leave boy alone.
怎么? 他不能解决自己的问题吗?
Can't the boy take care of himself?
一对一的问题 可以
One -to -one problem, yes.
五对一的问题 太过份
Five -to -one problem, too much ask anyone.
你是因此而不爽吗? 因为人多?
Is that what's bothering you, the odds?
很好解决呀 劳伦斯先生
Well, we can fix that.
-想打斗吗? -是 老师!
-Feel like matching, Mr. Lawrence? -Yes, Sensei!
不要打
No more fighting.
这是空手道道场 不是刺绣课
This is a karate dojo, not a knitting class.
你不能来我道场 撂下挑战就走人 老头子
You don't come in here, drop a challenge and leave, old man.
让这小子上场 否则我们就有大问题了
You get your boy on the mat, or you and I will have a problem.
太占优势 你的道场
Too much advantage, your dojo.
说个地方
Name a place.
锦标赛
Tournament.
你胆子真不小 老头
You've got real nerve, old man.
但我想我们可以接受
But I think we can accommodate you.
对吧 劳伦斯先生?
Can't we, Mr. Lawrence?
是 老师
Yes, Sensei.
去排队
Fall in.
再请求一件小事
Ask one more small request.
快说
Make it fast.
不要打扰男孩好让他受训
Ask leave boy alone to train.
你这个逼迫人的混蛋
You're a pushy little bastard, ain't you?
不过我喜欢
But I like that.
好 锦标赛前 不准有人碰那个吹牛皮的
No one touches the prima donna until the tournament.
-了解吗? -是 老师!
-Is that understood? -Yes, Sensei!
但如果你没出现…
But if you don't show...
那就别怪我们…
... then it's open season...
对他和你…
... on him...
不客气
... and you.
我不敢相信
I can't believe this.
-什么? -你把我弄进这种事
-I cannot believe this! -What?
你说你会替我解决的
What you just got me into. You said you'd make things better.
-我做啦 -哪算?
-I did. -How?
哪算? 我让你少挨两个月的揍
How? I saved you two months of beating.
棒透了 我真是等不及 现在我总算有事情可以期待了
Great, now I've got something to look forward to.
到你家还要多久?
How much further is your house?
另一条小路
Other side tracks.
什么 你也插手石油业吗?
Are you in the oil business, too?
不是什么都能以外貌决定的
Not everything is as seem.
这地方好像纽沃 我们来这里干嘛?
Reminds me of Newark. What are we going to do here?
开始训练
Start training.
很多事要做
Much work be done.
比赛很快就到了
Tournament here before you know it.
这正是我害怕的
That's what I'm afraid of.
那老师是个疯子 你真认为我能打败他?
That teacher was really wacko. You really think I can beat that guy?
不重要
No matter.
疯老师的拳头就是他的态度
Wacko teacher attitude rest in fist.
笨 但是真的
Stupid, but fact of life.
输赢都不重要
Win, lose, no matter.
你好好打 赢得尊重
You make good fight, earn respect.
-那就没人来烦你 -我倒下了 他们会把我埋了
-Then nobody bother. -They'll bury me where I fall.
总之问题是解决了 在这等
Either way, problem solved. Wait right here.
好棒
This is great.
-我昨晚忘记把这还你 -不 你留着
-I forgot to give you this back. -You keep.
谢谢
Thanks a lot.
-好了吗? -嗯 我想是吧
-Ready? -Yeah, I guess so.
丹尼尔桑 要谈谈
Daniel -san, must talk.
走在路上
Walk on road.
走右边 安全 走左边 安全
Walk right side, safe. Walk left side, safe.
走中间 早晚会…像葡萄一样被压扁
Walk middle, sooner or later, you get squished just like grape.
空手道也一样
Here, karate same thing.
你会空手道…或你不会
Either you karate do, yes, or karate do, no.
你"我想是"空手道…会像葡萄
You karate do, "guess so, " just like grape.
懂了?
Understand?
对 我懂
Yeah, I understand.
准备好了?
Ready?
对 我准备好了
Yeah, I'm ready.
好
Yes.
一定要做神圣条约
First make sacred pact.
我保证教空手道 这是我的责任
I promise teach karate. That's my part.
你保证会学 我说 你做 不问问题
You promise learn. I say, you do, no questions.
那是你的责任
That's your part.
成交?
Deal?
成交
It's a deal.
第一 洗所有的车 然后打蜡
First wash all the cars, then wax.
-我为什么要… -记得交易 不问问题
-Why do I have to... -Remember deal. No questions.
对 可是…
Yeah, but...
上蜡 右手 磨光 左手
Wax on right hand. Wax off left hand.
上蜡 磨光
Wax on, wax off.
用鼻子吸气 从嘴巴吐气
Breathe in through nose, out through mouth.
上蜡 磨光
Wax on, wax off.
别忘了呼吸 很重要
Don't forget to breathe. Very important.
上蜡 磨光
Wax on, wax off.
这些车哪来的?
Where did these cars come from?
底特律
Detroit.
磨光
Wax on...
上蜡 右手 画圆圈
... right hand make circle.
磨光 左手 圆圈
Wax off, left hand make circle.
上蜡 磨光
Wax on, wax off.
吸气 吐气
Breathe in, breathe out.
上蜡 磨光
Wax on, wax off.
宫城先生 我做完了
Mr. Miyagi, I'm finished.
你要检查吗?
You want to check these out?
宫城先生?
Mr. Miyagi?
哈罗?
Hello?
你在这里 我到处找你
I've been looking all over for you. Where've you been?
-你到哪去了? -我真不敢相信
-I don't believe it. -What?
-什么? 你要去哪? -我要去找那个混蛋 这该停止了
-Where are you going? -I'm going to find that idiot.
-不 我会应付这一切的 -直到下一次?
-No, it's been taken care of. -Until next time.
-不会有下次 -他们来了
-There isn't going to be a "next time." -There they are.
好 看着 嗨 各位 怎么样? 真高兴见到你们
Watch this. Hey, guys, it's good to see you.
强尼 打伤你眼睛真是抱歉 汤米 你肩膀没事吧?
Sorry about your eye, Johnny. Your shoulder okay, Tommy?
你们最好小心 别再添更多淤青了 好吗?
You guys be careful not to step in front of any more buses.
慢着 记得老师说的话? 你得等到比赛
Hold it. Remember what Sensei said? Wait for the tournament.
一定是跟懦弱鬼散步周!
It must be "Take a Worm for a Walk" week.
是你打伤他们的?
You did all that damage?
你不知道在浴室里许的愿 都会成真吗?
When you make a wish in the shower, it always comes true.
-我真该闭嘴的 -不 我们有协议
-I should have kept my mouth shut. -No, we've got an agreement.
哦 什么协议?
Yeah? What's that?
他们同意不揍我…我保证不让我的血流到他们衣服上 就这样
They agreed not to beat up on me and I promised not to bleed on them.
-我不信 -那我该怎么做 呻吟抱怨吗?
-I don't believe you. -What can I do, moan and groan?
-别人都会这样 -谁会听呢?
-Anybody else would. -Who'd listen anyway?
我
Me.
真的?
Really?
-你这个星期六晚上想听吗? -当然
-You feel like listening on Saturday night? -Sure.
好 太棒了
Great! So Saturday night...
那就星期六晚上 我们出去 我们好好去玩…或做点什么…
... we'll go out, we'll have a good time. We'll do whatever.
-那是什么 你的地址? -没错
-Is that your address? -You got it.
这在哪里?
Where is this?
-我得走了 -好
-I've got to go. -Okay.
好 待会再跟你聊
I'll talk to you later. Great.
太好了
All right.
哈瑞斯先生 我可以跟你谈谈吗? 拉罗素 第三段历史课上的
Mr. Harris, can I talk to you? LaRusso. Third period history class.
我想跟你说 那天我在课堂上真的学到很多…关於印地安人抢马的事 那实在太棒了
I wanted to tell you, I really got a lot out of that lecture about the Indians.
我正在跟我朋友们说…现你能给我们稍微解说一下吗?
I was telling my buddies about it. Could you give us a quick review?
-当然 我现在有空 -那太好了
-Sure, I'm free this period. -Great for me.
我得走了
No, I got to go.
那就只剩下你跟我了 不过没关系 我解释给你听…
I guess that leaves you and me, but that's all right.
然后你再去告诉你朋友们
You can tell them about it later.
高原印地安人是全北美洲里 非常原始的部族
The Plains Indians were a very primitive tribe...
去吧 大众情人
Come on, Casanova.
-嗨 嗨 你好吗? -我很好
-Hi, how are you doing? -Good.
-你真漂亮 -谢谢
-You look nice. -Thank you.
你有客人
You've got company.
那是我父母 来 我带你去见他们
Those are my parents. Come on, I want you to meet them.
好
Great.
-哈罗 甜心 -嗨 爸
-Hello, sweetheart. -Hi, Dad.
爸妈 这是丹尼尔拉罗素
This is Daniel LaRusso.
-他们是我爸妈 密尔斯先生太太 -丹尼尔 你好 嗨
-My parents, Mr. And Mrs. Mills. -How do you do, Daniel?
-哈罗 -很高兴见到你们
-Hello, Daniel. -Nice to meet you.
-甜心 你们要去哪? -我不知道 我们要去哪?
-Where are you going? -I don't know. Where are we going?
我不知道 随便你想去
I don't know. Wherever you want.
-高尔夫乐园? -好啊 我们就去高尔夫乐园
-Golf N' Stuff? -We're going to Golf N' Stuff, then.
别担心那个 我以为你会把它修好?
Don't worry about that. Weren't you going to have that fixed?
我是 我会的
I am. I was. I will.
-丹尼尔 你住安西诺吗? -什么? 安西诺? 不
-You live in Encino, Daniel? -Encino? No.
-你住哪里? -在 嗯 罗瑟达那边
-Where do you live? -Out, like Reseda.
-那是你母亲? -对 是她
-And that's your mother? -Yeah, that's her.
嗨!
Hi!
她在等我们 我们快走吧 很高兴认识你们
She's waiting for us. We'd better go. Nice to meet you.
-别太晚回家 甜心 -好 爸爸
-Not too late, sweetheart. -Okay, Dad.
我觉得好像呆瓜
-嗨 拉罗素太太 我叫艾莉 -嗨 艾莉 叫我露西欧
-Hi, Mrs. LaRusso. I'm Ali. -Hi, Ali. Call me Lucille.
-好 你家真漂亮 -谢谢
-That's a beautiful house you have. -Thanks.
-你会开手排吗? -会
-Can you drive a stick? -Yeah.
好 打二档 让车前进 等我说"开动"时你就开动
Put it into second, let it roll, and when I say "pop it, " pop it.
开动
"Pop it."
别担心 情况在控制中
Don't worry, it's all under control.
她很可爱 车子每次都这样
She's cute. It happens a lot.
好 拉罗素! 再推! 好 哈士奇!
Okay, LaRusso, push! On, you huskies!
好 开动!
Okay, pop it!
成功了 拉罗素!
We got it on the first!
高尔夫乐园 -家庭娱乐中心
商场 -游乐 -奖品
我11点来接你们 别玩得太晚 好好玩吧
I'll pick you up at 11:00. Please, don't be late. Have fun.
-看看那滑道 -我们下次再来玩
-Look at that slide. -We'll do that next time.
-为什么下次? -因为我们需要泳衣
-Why next time? -You need a bathing suit.
噢 对 泳衣
Oh, yeah. Bathing suits.
-你会打曲棍球吗? -不是很专业啦
-Do you play hockey? -Not professionally.
这是我到这里之后 最快乐的时刻了
This is the best time I've had since I've been here.
-我想我们得再来一次 -当然
-We'll have to do it again. -Definitely.
嘿 漂亮小姐 你好吗?
Hey, good looking. How are you?
好 太酷了!
Good. This is cool.
-我刚得到的 你要兜风吗? -或许下次吧
-I just got it. You want a ride? -Some other time.
-你确定? -丹尼尔 这是艾迪 艾迪 这是丹尼尔
-Are you sure? -Daniel, this is Eddie. Eddie, Daniel.
-你好 -好
-How are you doing, Daniel? -Good.
-嗨 艾莉! -嗨
-Hey, Ali! How's it going? -Hi, guys.
-还好吗? -来这里 我们要去山庄 你要不要来?
-How are you doing? -Want to come with us?
不 我不去 你们好好去玩吧
No, I don't think so. You guys have a good time.
-我们挤得下的 -我明天打电话给你
-We'll make room. -I'll call you tomorrow.
你的小朋友也可以一起来 如果他妈咪准他的话
Your little friend can come, if it's okay with his mommy.
嗨 孩子们
Hi, kids.
-妈咪 丹尼尔可不可以去兜风呀? -我真的很喜欢你的车 拉罗素太太
-Hey, Mommy, can Daniel come for a ride? -I really like your car.
-你可以去的 -我不想 可以吗?
-You could've gone. -I didn't want to.
-又没什么了不起 -如果我真想去 我会去的
-It's no big deal. -Lf I'd wanted to go, I would have.
对我没差 随便你要做什么 我不在乎
It makes no difference to me. Do what you want, I don't care.
好漂亮
This is beautiful.
宫城先生 这真棒 你这里有真的鱼
Mr. Miyagi, this is great. You've got real fish in there.
太漂亮了
This is outrageous.
我以为中李中国餐厅已经够棒了 你比他还厉害
I thought Chung Lee's restaurant was nice. You beat his act.
看这个 这像是天堂 你自己做的吗?
This is paradise. Did you do this yourself?
还有这些小手鼓?
Are these bongos?
我会喔
No, I got it.
哈拉克须纳 哈拉克须纳
"Hare Krishna"
丹尼尔桑 你真好玩
Daniel -san, you much humour.
-这些是什么? -日式磨沙器
-What are these? -Japanese sander.
-你拿来做什么? -你问得真好
-What do you do with them? -Funny you should ask.
右圆圈…
Right circle.
左圆圈
Left circle.
-前后动作不是简单多了吗? -但你要画圆圈
-It'd be easier going back and forth. -But you go circle.
右圆圈
Right circle.
左圆圈
Left circle.
右圆圈 左圆圈
Right circle, left circle.
吸气 吐气
Breathe in, breathe out.
右圆圈 左圆圈
Right circle, left circle.
吸气 吐气
Breathe in, breathe out.
整片地板 右圆圈 左圆圈
Whole floor. Right circle, left circle.
右圆圈
Right circle.
左圆圈
Left circle.
吸气 吐气
Breathe in, breathe out.
很好
Very good.
-尖刺都不见了 -对
-Splinters all gone. -Yeah
我做完了
I'm finished.
宫城先生 我累死了
Mr. Miyagi, I'm beat.
我的肩膀
My shoulders.
好
Good.
回家 休息 明早再来
Go home, get rest.
早上开始 6点
Come morning, start early. 6:00.
用苍蝇拍不是简单多了吗?
Wouldn't a fly swatter be easier?
能用筷子夹到苍蝇的人…能成就任何事
Man who catch fly with chopsticks, accomplish anything.
你夹到过吗?
Did you ever catch one?
还没
Not yet.
我来试?
Could I try?
随你
If wish.
嘿 宫城先生 看!
Hey, Mr. Miyagi, look!
好狗运
You, beginner luck.
这表示我可以成就任何事 很简单嘛
I guess that means I can accomplish anything, right? No sweat.
但首先你要完成漆围h
First you accomplish paint fence.
只用手腕
All in wrist.
手腕向上 向下
Wrist up. Wrist down.
只用手腕 上 下
All in wrist. Up, down, long stroke.
拉长 很好 上 下
Very good. Up, down.
不要看我 看围h
No look me, look fence.
上…
Up...
下
... down.
手腕要弯 往下时你就压弯它 对
Bend the wrist. Downstroke, you bend. See? Good.
拉长 上 下 很好
Long stroke. Up, down. Very good.
腔盖要弯 往下
Bend your knees. Down.
上…
Up.
很好 丹尼尔桑 别忘了呼吸
Very good, Daniel -san. Don't forget to breathe.
吸 吐
In, out.
上…
Up...
…下
... down.
上 下
Up, down.
上…
Up...
…下
... down.
上…
Up...
…下
... down.
很好 丹尼尔桑
Very good, Daniel -san.
上 下
Up, down.
上…
Up...
…下
... down.
小片的用左手 大片的用右手
Small board, left hand. Big board, right hand.
-但我快漆完了 -所有围h
-I'm almost done. -All of fence.
大片的用右手 小片的用左手
Big board, right hand. Small board, left hand.
上 下
Up, down.
全部做完了
All finished.
很漂亮吧?
It looks pretty good, huh?
两面都漆了?
Both sides?
还没
Not yet.
丹尼尔桑 做得很好
Daniel -san. Very good job.
明早来 早点开始
Come morning. Start early.
上!
Up...
下!
... down.
上…
Up...
…下
... down.
漆房子
不要上下漆! 要左右漆 一半左手 一半右手 -宫城
可恶! 真不敢相信!
Damn it! I can't believe this.
那里没漆到
Missed spot.
哪里?
What spot?
-你怎么没跟我说你去钓鱼了? -我走时你不在
-You didn't tell me you were going fishing. -You not here when I go.
-或许我也会想去 你有没有想过? -你要练空手道
-Maybe I wanted to go. -You karate training.
我什么? 我是你该死的奴隶
I'm what? I'm being your goddamn slave!
-我们有过交易 -所以?
-We made a deal here. -So?
你应该教我…我应该来学的 记得吗?
"So"? You're supposed to teach and I'm supposed to learn.
四天来我累得半死 什么狗屁也没学到!
Four days I've been busting my ass, I haven't learned a thing.
-你已学了很多 -我学到替你的地板磨沙…
-You learn plenty. -I've learned to sand your decks.
替你的车打蜡 漆你的房子 你的围h 我学了一大堆
I've waxed your car, I paint your house, paint your fence.
-别只从外貌来看事情 -狗屁! 我要回家了
-Not everything is as seems. -Bullshit! I'm going home, man.
丹尼尔桑
Daniel -san!
-什么? -回来
-What? -Come here.
-做磨地板给我看 -我手臂动不了了 不行吗?
-Show me sand the floor. -I can't move my arm, all right?
你在做什么?
What are you doing?
-现在做磨地板给我看 -你是怎么弄的?
-Now show me sand the floor. -How did you do that?
做!
Show!
磨地板?
Sand the floor?
站起来
Stand up.
做磨地板给我看
Show me sand the floor.
磨地板
Sand the floor.
大圆圈
Big circle. Sand the floor.
磨地板
Sand the floor.
现在做打蜡 磨光
Now show me wax on, wax off.
-打蜡 磨光 -打蜡 磨光
-Wax on, wax off. -"Wax on, wax off! "
打蜡…
Wax on...
…磨光
... wax off.
专心 看着我眼睛
Concentrate. Look in my eyes.
手要稳 姆指在里面
Lock your hand, thumb inside.
打蜡…
Wax on...
…磨光
... wax off.
打蜡…
Wax on...
…磨光
... wax off.
打蜡
Wax on.
磨光
Wax off.
做漆围h给我看 上 下
Show me paint the fence. Up, down.
上
Up.
下
Down.
上
Up.
下
Down.
换边 看眼睛 一直看着眼睛
Other side. Look eye. Always look eye!
做漆房子给我看 左 右
Show me paint the house. Side, side.
手要稳 左 右
Lock wrist. Side, side.
左 右
Side, side.
做打蜡 磨光
Show me wax on, wax off.
做漆围h
Show me paint the fence.
做左 右
Show me side, side.
做磨地板
Show me sand the floor.
看着眼睛 要看着眼睛
Look eye! Always look eye.
明天回来
Come back tomorrow.
学习平衡! 去水里 踢水 学平衡
Learn balance. Go water, kick. Learn balance.
你在那些柱子上做什么?
What were you doing on those stumps?
-这是鹤功 -有用吗?
-Called crane technique. -Does it work?
做得对 没人挡得住
If do right, no can defence.
你能教我吗?
Could you teach me?
先学站 再学飞
First learn stand, then learn fly.
-自然定律 丹尼尔桑 不是我的 -你从哪学的?
-Nature rule, Daniel -san, not mine. -Who taught you?
-父亲教的 -你父亲一定很了不起 -对
-Father teach. -You must have had some father.
-看 那小子找了个日本鬼子 -小子 他会什么功夫?
-Look, the kid's got a pet Nip. -He know any tricks, kid?
请借过 孩子会冷 要走
Excuse, please. Boy cold, must leave.
请拿走瓶子
Kindly remove bottle.
请你自己做 摩托先生
Kindly do it yourself, Mr. Moto.
你怎么弄的?
How did you do that?
不知道 第一次
Don't know. First time.
嗨 你
Hey, you!
-不坏嘛 绝对可进校队 -你让我射门得分的
-Hey, not bad. Definitely varsity material. -You let me.
我正想叫你星期五晚上去玩滑道 我7点去接你?
Should we try the slide on Friday? I could pick you up about 7:00.
我要在爸妈的俱乐部那里吃晚餐
I'm having dinner with my parents at the country club.
但9点半前会结束 你到前门等我
I'll be done by 9:30. Meet me out front.
-可以吗? -当然
-Is that cool? -Yeah.
强尼 这儿
Johnny, over here!
-怎么了? -我又听到脑里那个声音了
-What's the matter? -It's that little voice again.
假装你聋了 安西诺橡树俱乐部 9点半
Pretend you're deaf. Encino Oaks Country Club. 9:30.
星期五? 好
Friday? Great.
-棒呀 跛脚球员 -嗨 艾莉
-Hi, Ali. -"Hi, Ali."
我一定疯了
I've got to be nuts.
好 停在这里 下锚
Okay, here. Stop. Throw anchor.
好 站着鞠躬
Good. Stand bow.
不是"鞠躬" 是前舷
Not bow. Bow!
-上! -什么 上去那边?
-Up! -What, up front?
摇摆
Make block.
左 右 上 下
Left, right. Up, down.
两边 吸气 吐气
Side, side. Breathe in, breathe out.
别惊动鱼儿
And no scare fish.
我何时可以学出拳?
When do I learn how to punch?
最好先学平衡
Better learn balance.
平衡是关键
Balance is key.
平衡好 空手道就好 一切都好
Balance good, karate good. Everything good.
平衡不好 最好收拾回家去 懂吗?
Balance bad, better pack up, go home. Understand?
是 我懂
Yeah, I understand.
你小时候有跟人打过架吗?
Did you ever get into fights when you were a kid?
多了
Plenty.
-但跟我的问题不一样吧? -打架都是一样的
-It wasn't like the problem I have, right? -Fighting, fighting. Same, same.
但你会空手道
But you knew karate.
人外有人
Someone always know more.
你是说 你也有害怕打架的时候?
There were times when you were scared to fight?
每次都怕 宫城讨厌打架
Always scared. Miyagi hate fighting.
-对 但你喜欢空手道 -那怎样?
-But you like karate. -So?
空手道就是打架 你练来打架
Karate's fighting, you train to fight.
你这么想?
That what you think?
不
No.
那为何练习?
Then why train?
所以我才不必跟人打架
So I won't have to fight.
宫城对你有信心
Miyagi have hope for you.
-我什么时候可以学出拳? -要学出拳…
-When do I learn how to punch? -Learn how punch...
-先学把身体弄干! -不!
-... when learn how keep dry! -No!
丹尼尔桑 你全身都湿透啦!
Daniel -san, you're all wet behind ear!
你干嘛 疯了吗?
Are you crazy?
你疯了!
You're crazy.
跟强尼出问题了?
Trouble with Johnny?
-你们两个小情侣有问题吗? -我们才不是情侣
-You two lovebirds having problems? -We're not lovebirds.
-爸 现在几点? -大概9点40分
-What time is it? -It's about 9:40.
-我得走了 -你有约会?
-I've got to go. -Do you have a date?
-跟谁? -爸 是个朋友
-With whom? -A friend.
不是那个罗瑟达的男孩吧
Not that boy from Reseda.
对 他是住罗瑟达
Yeah, he's from Reseda.
他人很好 你不用担心
He's a nice guy. It's no big deal.
甜心 你霸占了这个最帅的男人好久了
Honey, you've monopolised the best -looking man here long enough.
-嗨 -嗨
-Hi. -Hi.
听着 我在想 或许我们可以停止吵架
I've been thinking, maybe we can call a truce.
我又没在打仗 失陪了
I'm not at war. Excuse me.
至少跳完一支舞吧?
Could we please finish the dance?
安西诺橡树俱乐部
不准你再对我做这种事!
Don't you ever do that to me again!
我不知道你会唱歌 宫城先生 你好吗?
I didn't know you were a singer. How are you doing?
丹尼尔桑 进来
Daniel -san, come inside.
-你唱的是什么歌? -日本蓝调
-What's that song you were singing? -Japanese blues.
跟往事干杯
Kampai.
万岁
Banzai!
敬小树
To baby trees.
不是盆栽 万岁
Not bonsai. Banzai!
万岁
Banzai.
Banzai!
-万岁 -勉强
-Banzai! -Close enough.
-我们在庆祝什么? -周年纪念
-What are we celebrating here? -Anniversary.
谁的周年纪念?
Whose anniversary?
是你太太? 我不知道你结婚了
Is this your wife? I didn't know you were married.
-超漂亮的 对吧? -对 她真漂亮
-Damn beautiful, don't you think? -Yeah, she's pretty.
我第一次看到她…
First time I saw her...
是在夏威夷的蔗田
... was cane field, Hawaii.
漂亮
Beautiful.
也是很棒的砍蔗手
Damn good cane cutter, too.
她现在在哪?
Where is she now?
要喝酒
Drink, drink.
丹尼尔桑
Daniel -san.
看
Look, look.
第一个美国籍的宫城 正等着出生
First American -born Miyagi waiting to be born.
喝酒!
Drink, drink.
宫城中士!
"Sergeant Miyagi!
是 长官
"Yes, sir!
长官 宫城中士报告 杀了很多德国兵
"Sergeant Miyagi reporting. Killed many Jerry Germans, sir.
宫城中士
"Sergeant Miyagi.
是 长官?
"Yes, sir.
遗憾通知你
"Regret to inform...
太太 儿子…分娩时的并发症
"... wife have complications at birth."
并发症 但没医生来
Complications. No doctor came.
自由之土 勇敢之乡
Land of free, home of brave.
没医生来
No doctor came.
军队将日本人送往曼扎拿
宫城先生
Mr. Miyagi.
没事吧?
Are you okay?
很遗憾通知您…1944年11月2日…
"We regret to inform you that on November 2, 1944...
在曼扎拿强制疏散中心…
"... at the Manzanar Relocation Center...
您太太和新生儿子死於…
"... your wife and newborn son died...
"分娩时的并发症"
"... due to complications arising from childbirth."
"英勇"
"Valour."
丹尼尔桑…
Daniel -san
出拳的秘密
Secret to punch...
集中力量…全身力量…
... make power of whole body...
集中於2公分处 这里
... fit inside one inch, here.
力量 全身 2公分处
Power, whole body, one inch, here.
这里 现在
Now punch.
用力打
Hard.
怎么了? 你是小女生吗?
You some kind of girl or something?
出拳! 用力打! 不要只有手臂 用全身
Punch! Drive a punch. Not just arm. Whole body.
臀部 腿部 用全力
Hip, leg, drive a punch. Make kiai.
用全身力气 现在再打
Give you power. Now drive punch.
-嗨 哈 -再来
-Kiai. -Once more.
很好 丹尼尔桑
Very good, Daniel -san.
很不错吧?
Hey, pretty good?
看这个
Look at this.
等等!
Wait. Daniel -san.
你觉得怎样 宫城先生?
What do you think?
我告诉你宫城觉得怎样 我觉得你跳太多了
I tell you what Miyagi think, I think you dance around too much.
我觉得你话太多了 我觉得你不够专心
I think you talk too much. I think you no concentrate enough.
要努力的地方多着呢 比赛就快到了
Lots of work to be done. Tournament just around corner.
来 站起来
Come, stand up.
现在准备 专心 集中力量
Steady, concentrate. Focus power.
出拳
Drive a punch.
出拳 丹尼尔桑
Drive a punch, Daniel -san.
祝你生日快乐
"Happy birthday to you
祝丹尼尔桑生日快乐
"Happy birthday, dear Daniel -san
祝你生日快乐
"Happy birthday to you"
许个愿
Make wish.
我知道要许什么愿
I know what I'm wishing for.
很好!
Very good.
一号生日礼物
Number one birthday present.
宫城先生 怎么搞的? 你不需要送我东西的
Mr. Miyagi, what did you do? You didn't have to do this.
这是什么? 我猜不出
What is this? I have no idea.
太棒了
Mr. Miyagi, this is great.
这从哪来的?
Where did this come from?
宫城太太很久以前做的
Mrs. Miyagi make, long time ago.
如果你想要回这个贴片 我会了解的
If you ever want this patch back, I'll understand.
我知道你会了解
I know you understand.
试穿
Try on.
太漂亮了 真棒
This is beautiful. This is great.
所以你认为我有机会赢得比赛?
Do you think I stand a chance at the tournament?
宫城怎么想不重要 宫城不去打架
Not matter what Miyagi think. Miyagi not fighting.
我不太确定我空手道学得够不够
I don't know if I know enough karate.
感觉正确
Feeling correct.
你还真会让人有信心嘛
You sure know how to make a guy feel confident.
你信任你所知的质量 而不是数量
You trust the quality of what you know, not quantity.
你今天拿到驾照?
Today you get driver's licence?
对! 看看这个
Yeah, look at this.
不错吧
Check that out.
"丹尼尔拉罗素"
"Daniel LaRusso."
恭喜
Congratulations.
谢谢 可以合法开车 对吧?
Thanks. The kid's legal, now.
我不知道你有个甜心
I never know you have sweetheart.
不 我没有
No, I don't.
看起来很配
Look good together.
不同 但一样
Different, but same.
不 不同就是不同
No. Different, but different.
真可惜你妈不在这里
Too bad mother not here.
可恶!
Shoot!
-糟了 -怎么了?
-Shoot! Damn! -What's matter?
我得走了 我应该要去找我妈的 她要替我做个惊喜蛋糕
I've got to go. My mother is making a surprise cake for me.
-宫城了解 -我不该知道这事 可恶
-Miyagi understand. -I wasn't supposed to know. Damn it.
-没关系 -真是抱歉
-That's okay. -I'm sorry.
宫城也有过母亲
Miyagi once have mother, too.
去外面 有东西给你看
Go outside. Something show you.
-什么? -二号礼物
-What? -Number two present.
二号礼物?
Number two present?
你不需要给我东西的 你已经给我很多了
You don't have to give me anything. You've given me enough already.
真的 我说真的
No really, I'm serious.
选吧
Choose.
不
Oh, no.
伤害老人的感情
Hurt old man feeling.
-选吧 -噢 哇!
-Choose. -Oh, wow.
宫城先生…
Mr. Miyagi
我真不敢相信!
I can't believe it.
哇 太棒的礼物了
What a gift!
天哪
Oh, boy.
只要记住
Just remember
驾照永不能取代…眼睛 耳朵 和头脑
A licence never replace eye, ear and brain.
怎么了?
What matter?
我突然怕起来 你知道 比赛等等那些事情
I'm just scared. The tournament and everything.
你记得学过平衡吗?
You remember lesson about balance?
是的
Yeah.
那不只是针对空手道而已
Lesson not just karate only.
那适於整个人生
Lesson for whole life.
有平衡的人生…
Whole life have a balance.
一切都会变好
Everything be better.
懂了?
Understand?
对 我懂
Yeah, I understand.
噢 哇
Oh, wow.
你是我有过最好的朋友
You're the best friend I ever had.
你…
You...
也还不错
... pretty okay, too.
去
Go.
去找平衡
Go find the balance.
好
OK
-万岁 丹尼尔桑 -万岁
-Banzai, Daniel -san! -Banzai!
爱情测验 测验你的性感外貌
你们两个 别开枪! 不!
I give up. Don't shoot! No.
-别丢下我在这里 我受伤了 -或许你会死呢
-Don't leave me. I'm wounded. -Good, maybe you'll die.
-我只是想跟你道歉 -好 你道过歉了
-I just wanted to apologise. -Fine, you apologised.
-你知道 我拿到驾照了 -了不起呀
-I got my licence. -Whoop -dee -doo.
-你怎么了? -你要我为这个后空翻还是怎样?
-What's with you? -What do you expect? Cartwheels?
不 我只是要点礼貌罢了 还是开名车的人都没有礼貌?
I just expected some courtesy, or is that only for people with fancy cars?
她对你没兴趣啦!
Can't you take a hint?
怎么? 真话伤人吗?
Does the truth hurt?
-你真的这样认为的是吧? -我知道是这样
-You really think that's it? -I know it is.
-你错了 -我当然错了
-You're wrong. -I bet I'm wrong.
我跟你约会 不是因为车子或你住的地方
I didn't go out with you because of a car or where you live.
说到这个 那你为何跟我约会?
Okay, while we're on the subject, why did you then?
为什么?
Why did you?
因为我以为你跟我很不一样
I thought maybe you and me were different.
我住罗瑟达 你住山庄 这就是我们不同之处
I'm from Reseda, you're from the hills, that's how we're different.
不是这个意思 何不承认…你无法接受事实?
Admit that you just can't handle the situation the way it is.
我可以 你却不行
I can handle it fine. You can't.
你干嘛那么神经质? 她一直对你都很好
What makes you so sensitive? She's never been anything but nice to you.
-她利用我去让那个谁吃醋 -她不喜欢他
-She used me to make him jealous. -She doesn't even like him.
原来在俱乐部那样亲吻 叫做不喜欢?
Who could tell, the way their faces were stuck together at the country club?
没错 你没待到令人兴奋的结局出现
Right, you didn't stick around for the exciting conclusion.
-结局? 他伸手摸她屁股? -她的右勾拳
-What, his hand on her ass? -Her right hook.
你以为她扭伤手腕是修指甲造成的吗?
You think she sprained her wrist doing her nails?
-她打他了? -这样说还客气了
-She hit him? -That's an understatement.
-她为什么不说? -她没必要说吧?
-Why didn't she say something? -She shouldn't have to, should she?
嘿 拳击手
Hey, slugger.
听着 我是混蛋
Look, I'm a jerk.
你是混蛋
You are a jerk.
所以你原谅我了?
So, am I forgiven?
我没听见
I don't hear anything.
听起来好像是
Sounds like a "yes" to me.
转过来
Come here.
我猜你知道明天的比赛
I guess you know about the tournament tomorrow.
谁不知道?
Who doesn't?
很蠢吧?
Dumb move, huh?
不一定
Not necessarily.
没人替我加油
I don't have much of a cheering section.
你有我呀
You got me.
反正我大概第一场比赛就会被打扁了
I'll probably get killed in the first match.
那我们就可以早点走了
So, we'll leave early.
-我有东西要给你看 -什么?
-I've got something to show you. -What?
-你喜欢吗? -你的? 你是当真的?
-How do you like it? -Is it yours? Are you serious?
-太漂亮了! -没错
-It's beautiful. -It sure is.
-噢 天哪! -钥匙拿去
-My God. -Here you go.
-你要我开? -这可是80年代耶
-You want me to drive? -It's the '80s!
-要启动 你要按那个钮 把钥匙插进去… -你真了不起
-To start, you push that button. -You're incredible.
现在踩离合器 开灯 不 那个
Press the clutch. Get the lights, no that one.
好 朝你往下的就是一档 现在慢慢放掉刹车
Good. Down is first. Let it out slow.
这样就对了
Hold on!
好啦 来罗! 太棒了 可以开多快?
This is awesome. How fast does it go?
最好不要试
Let's not find out.
-你空手道什么带? -带?
-What belt are you? -Why matter?
有什么关系? 这是自由参赛 只有棕带以上才能参加
This is open division, it's only for brown belt or above.
他是黑带
Boy black belt.
你最好快点 要开始了 往里面走 然后左转
You'd better hustle. They're starting. Down the hall, to your left.
-里面见! -好
-I'll see you inside. -Okay.
抱歉 裁判先生
Excuse me, Mr. Referee.
不是宫城 是宫城
This is not "Miyaji." Miyagi.
宫城
Miyagi.
好 谢谢
Okay, thank you.
哟 各位 看看谁在这里 我们的小朋友 丹妮儿
Well, look who we have here. Our little friend Danielle.
哈罗 丹妮儿
Hello, Danielle.
怎么回事? 妈咪没帮你穿好衣服?
What's the matter? Mommy not here to dress you?
我在跟你说话 小子 来呀 来打呀!
I'm talking to you, punk. Come on, make a move.
嘿 等上场再打
Hey, save it for the ring.
走吧
Come on!
-好吧 -我们走
-All right. -Let's go.
走
Come on.
不管有无点数…
Points or no points...
你都死定了
... you're dead meat.
我叫你们出去!
I said out!
死定了
Dead meat.
少来了 我猜他会哭的
Way to go, I think he's gonna cry.
自由参赛第一场的胜利者是 路卡斯史奈德
The winner of the first match in the open division is Rufus Schneider.
-嗨 宫城先生 -丹尼尔桑 快点来 比赛要开始了
-Mr. Miyagi. -Hurry. Tournament starting.
这是哪来的?
Where'd we get this?
丹尼尔拉罗素
Daniel LaRusso...
-佛祖提供的 -请立刻到3号场地报到
-Buddha provide. -... please report to Ring 3.
-3号场地在哪? -那里
-Where's Ring 3? -Over there.
等等! 只有老师和学生 才能上比赛场地 抱歉
Hold it! Sorry, teachers and students only.
他不会说英文
He doesn't speak English...
没有她的翻译我听不懂他的指示 她是他的翻译
... and I can't understand his instructions without her. She's his translator.
-他说什么? -你让他想起在东京的舅舅
-What did he say? -You remind him of his uncle in Tokyo.
-我想应该没问题 什么? -他说你很好
-I guess it's okay. What? -He says you're very kind.
-谢谢 -不客气
-Thank you. -Welcome.
-这里的规则怎样? -不知道
-What are the rules here? -I don't know.
你第一次 我第一次
First time you, first time me.
我以为你知道这些事 以前也参加过
I figured you knew about this stuff. I figured you went to these before.
那我死定了
Great, I'm dead.
-你说你打过很多次 -求生 不是求点数
-You told me you fought a lot. -For life, not for points.
只要击中腰部以上就得点数
Everything above your waist is a point.
你可以攻击头部 胸部 腰部 和肋骨 懂吗?
You can hit the head, sternum, kidneys, ribs. Got it?
-希望如此 -你做得到的
-I hope so. -You can do it.
你们这些混蛋何时才会长大?
When are you jerks going to grow up?
-我要去哪? 这里这个吗? -3号
-Where am I, over here at this one? -Number 3.
-那个人跪在那里干嘛? -不知道
-What's that guy kneeling for? -I don't know.
-你什么事情都不知道吗? -打 赢得点数
-Don't you know anything? -Don't get hit.
鞠躬 面对面
Face. Bow. On guard.
开始!
Fight.
回到线上
Back on your line.
-坚强点 丹尼尔 -无点数 预备
-Be tough, Daniel. -Get Ready
加油! 坚强点!
Come on, be tough.
记得你要防卫 别想点数 专心 集中力量
Remember your defence. Points coming. Concentrate. Focus power.
记得平衡 好好去打
Remember balance. Make good fight.
警告走出场外 再出场就会失分
Run out of the ring once more, it'll cost you a point.
预备 准备好了?
On guard. Ready?
好 丹尼尔 得分 加油!
That's one, Daniel, come on.
再来
One more!
回到你的线上
Move back on your line.
赢得一点 回旋踢
That's one point, round kick.
太好了 丹尼尔! 你是最棒的!
Daniel, you're the best!
眼镜蛇凯
你完蛋了 死定了!
You're dead!
得点 获胜
Point! Winner!
拉罗素 -道区
获胜
Winner!
-要贴紧 -在这里
-It must be tight. -Yeah, right there.
-没想到我能撑这么久 -我也是
-I never thought I'd get this far. -Make two of us.
要是能赢会有多棒?
Wouldn't it be great if I won?
-你能活下来就很棒了 -什么意思 活下来?
-It'd be great if you survive. -What do you mean "survive"?
-对 只要我不动就好 -我们得走了 你得去签到 他们要开始了
-I'm fine as long as I don't move. -You've got to move now, they're starting.
要开始了? 什么意思 活下来?
Are they starting now? What do you mean "survive"?
各位先生女士…
Ladies and gentlemen...
请各位注意好吗?
... may I have your attention, please.
这是今天下午的第一场准决赛
This is the first semi -final match of the afternoon.
防守冠军 眼镜蛇凯的约翰劳伦斯…
Defending champion, John Lawrence of the Cobra Kai.
18岁以下金奖全谷区大赛的两次赢家
Two -time winner of the All Valley Under -18 Golden Trophy.
他将迎战罗克斯河谷空手道俱乐部的 丹尼多佛
He'll be facing Darryl Vidal of the Locust Valley Karate Club.
三点得胜 请双方入场好吗?
Three points wins. Contestants, please come to the ring.
祝两位好运
Good luck, gentlemen.
打他 强尼!
Go get him, Johnny.
嘿 小子 给他看看你的厉害!
Show him what you're made of.
两位面对我 鞠躬 面对面
Face me, gentlemen. Bow.
鞠躬 准备好了? 开始!
Face. Bow. Ready?
加油 强尼!
Come on, Johnny.
快 强尼 上 上
Fast, Johnny. Come on. Do it.
一点 劳伦斯
One point, Lawrence.
劳伦斯
Lawrence, back on the line.
回到线上
Way to go!
你还好吧?
Are you all right?
我没事
I'm okay.
一点 劳伦斯
One point, Lawrence.
很好 强尼
Good point, Johnny!
劳伦斯得点 获胜!
Point Lawrence. Winner!
下场准决赛将决定…谁将迎战防守冠军
The next semi -final determines who will face the defending champion.
宫城派空手道的…丹尼尔拉罗素能否…
Daniel LaRusso, of the Miyagi -do Karate.
挑战眼镜蛇凯的巴比布朗…
Bobby...
我要他重伤
... I want him out of commission.
可是老师 我打得过这小子
Sensei, I can beat this guy.
-我不要他被打 -可是我会失去资格!
-I don't want him beaten. -But I'll be disqualified!
重伤
Out of commission.
开始吧 两位!
Let's go, fellas. Good luck.
巴比 做你该做的!
Do what you got to do, Bobby!
鞠躬 准备好了吗?
Face. Bow. Ready?
两位等我指令再开始
Watch the control, gentlemen. Ready?
-丹尼尔 对不起! 我不是故意的! -我的腿!
-I'm sorry! I didn't mean it. -My leg!
-宫城先生 我的腿好痛! -丹尼尔桑 宫城在这里 没事
-Mr. Miyagi, my leg hurts. -Miyagi here.
眼镜蛇凯的巴比布朗 因蓄意重击对手…
Bobby Brown of the Cobra Kai has been disqualified...
而丧失资格 根据41-2条规定…
... for excessive and deliberate contact. Under rule 41-2...
丹尼尔拉罗素有15分钟回到比赛
... Daniel LaRusso has 15 minutes to return to the ring.
如果拉罗素无法比赛…
If he is unable to return...
约翰劳伦斯将获得冠军
... John Lawrence will win by default.
我去通知裁判
I'll inform the judges.
年轻人 你做得很好
You did well out there, young man.
该死的!
Damn it!
甜心 算了吧
Honey, forget it.
你打得很棒!
You were great.
我骄傲极了
I couldn't be prouder.
只是运气不好
It was just bad luck.
如果他们没有作弊 你会赢的
You would have won if they hadn't cheated.
让我静一静好吗?
Just leave me alone for a minute.
我们在外面等
We'll be outside.
宫城先生…
Mr. Miyagi...
你认为我有机会赢吗?
... you think I had a chance of winning?
输赢都不重要
Win, lose, no matter.
我不是这个意思
That's not what I mean.
很有机会
Had good chance.
你能不能像上次那样 让我的腿好起来?
Can you fix my leg with that thing you do?
不需要再打了
No need fight anymore.
-你已证明了 -什么? 证明我可以被打吗?
-You proved a point. -What, that I can take a beating?
只要我见到那些人 他们都会知道他们击败了我
Every time I see those guys, they'll know they got the best of me.
我再也不可能取得平衡 跟他们 跟艾莉…
I'll never have balance that way, not with them, not with Ali...
跟我自己都不会
... not with me.
嗯?
What?
闭上眼睛
Close eye.
好 各位先生女士…这是我们期待已久的时刻…
Ladies and gentlemen, this is the moment we've been waiting for.
丹尼尔拉罗素还要打?
Daniel LaRusso's going to fight?
Daniel LaRusso's going to fight!
这不正是比赛刺激的地方吗?
This is what it's all about, folks. You know it.
小子 腿怎么样?
How's the leg, son?
好! 大比赛来了!
All right. What a man!
最后比赛将决定…
The final match to determine...
谁能够获胜而得到…
... who'll emerge victor and champion...
全河谷区18岁以下空手道的冠军
... of the All Valley Under -18 Karate Championship.
丹尼尔拉罗素 宫城派空手道…
Daniel LaRusso, Miyaji -do Karate...
宫城派
Miyagi -do.
宫城派空手道…
Miyagi -do Karate.
迎战眼镜蛇凯的约翰劳伦斯
... versus John Lawrence of the Cobra Kai.
三点得胜 祝两位好运
Three points wins. Good luck, boys.
打吧 丹尼尔 你够强 你可以做到的!
Come on, Daniel! You've got this guy. You can do it.
面对我 鞠躬 面对面
Face me. Bow.
鞠躬 准备好了?
Face off. Bow. Ready?
-开始 -打倒他!
-Begin -Down down
没关系 强尼!
That's okay, Johnny.
劳伦斯 回来
Lawrence, return.
一点 拉罗素
One point, LaRusso.
你死定了
You're dead.
-好 丹尼尔! -开始!
-Ah Daniel! -Hey
你抓到他了 丹尼尔!
Daniel, you've got him!
斩击得点! 拉罗素得了两点!
Point! Jab! That's two for LaRusso.
中场休息! 去老师那边
Time out. Go to your sensei.
转身 跪下
Turn, kneel.
强尼 你是最棒的
Johnny, you're a creampuff!
从下面扫踢他伤处
Sweep the leg.
你有问题吗?
You have a problem with that?
可是 老师…
No, Sensei.
不心软
No mercy.
再来
One more!
拉罗素得两点 劳伦斯无点
Two points LaRusso. Lawrence nothing.
好!
劳伦斯得一点 二比一 拉罗素领先
One point Lawrence. 2-1, LaRusso.
好了? 开始!
来呀 打得好!
踢旁边 劳伦斯得一点 二比二
Kick to the side. One point Lawrence. 2-2.
出场 回来
Out of bounds. Come back in.
强尼 打败他!
Destroy him, Johnny!
丹尼尔 你做得到! 加油!
Come on, Daniel, you can do it!
好 强尼!
起来 坚强点!
Come on, Daniel. Be strong.
-你还好吗? -对 我可以
-Are you okay? -Yeah, I'm okay.
谁赢了下个点数就会是新冠军
Whoever wins the next point will be our new champion.
无点 准备
击倒他! 强尼
Finish him, Johnny!
结束了 强尼 你赢了!
It's over, Johnny! You did it!
你确定你可以? 你能继续吗?
Are you okay? Can you go on?
把他装进尸袋!
Get him a body bag!
警告违规踢腔盖
Warning for illegal contact to the knee.
强尼 打败他 别心软!
解决他!
Finish him!
获胜!
Winner!
新诞生的冠军 丹尼尔拉罗素!
The new champion!
-你很棒 拉罗素 -谢谢
-You're all right, LaRusso. -Thanks a lot.
嗨 宫城先生 我们成功了!
Mr. Miyagi, we did it. All right!